AJIN KRISHNA

Address Chennai, India Phone +91 8138062216 Email ajinaju2837@gmail.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/ajinkrishna09101998

OBJECTIVE

Mechanical designer with 5 years of experience specializing in Surface & Pattern design with knowledge in Moulding, Machining & 3D printing. Seeking a challenging position in a progressive organization where I can utilize my technical expertise and creativity to contribute to innovative product development and enhance overall efficiency.

SKILLS

- Proficient in 3D CAD software such as 3D EXPERIENCE, CATIA & AUTOCAD.
- Strong understanding of mechanical design principles and practices.
- Experience in creating detailed engineering drawings & assembly drawings.
- Knowledge of manufacturing processes.
- Knowledge in drawing verification with manufacturing feasibility & quality assurance.

EXPERIENCE

July 2023 - PRESENT

OFFICER - TECHNICAL (R&D)

MRF TYRES R&D, CHENNAI

• Working alongside the design automation team to define mold specifications, incorporating design constraints, tolerances, and manufacturing considerations.

July 2021 - July 2023

JUNIOR OFFICER - TECHNICAL (R&D)

MRF TYRES R&D. CHENNAL

- Advanced 3D surface parametric modelling for various patterns.
- Developed and designed complex variable pitch tyre patterns for major OEMs.
- Collaborated with stakeholders including engineers, technicians and manufacturing personnel to ensure smooth product development and production processes.
- Participated in design reviews and provided technical recommendations for product improvements.
- Knowledge of various mould manufacturing processes EDM, Casting, CNC Machining, Additive manufacturing 3D printing.
- Knowledge in SAP documentation & Material management.
- Collaborated closely with the team to communicate project requirements and specifications to mould vendors accurately.

July 2018 - July 2021

SUPERVISOR - TECHNICAL (R&D)

MRF TYRES R&D, CHENNAI

- Achieved design skills on Tyre cavity, pattern and surface design in Catia-Generative Shape design module.
- Expertise in Design for Manufacturing (DFM) principles, optimizing product designs for efficient manufacturing processes and cost-effective production.
- Proficient in interpreting and applying GD&T principles and standards to engineering drawings and designs.

EDUCATION

June 2015 - April 2018 DIPLOMA - MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Government Polytechnic College Kozhikode, Kerala, India

Scored 8.66 CGPA

June 2012 - April 2015 TECHNICAL HIGH SCHOOL - ELECTRONICS

Technical High School Vadakara, Kerala, India

Scored 95% marks

SOFTWARES

- Catia Generative Shape Design
- Dassault 3D Experience
- AutoCAD
- SAP
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Office

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name Ajin Krishna

Gender Male

Date of Birth 09.10.1998

Marital Status Single

Nationality Indian

Languages Known English, Malayalam, Tamil, Hindi

Work Experience 5 years